Guide to the Baldwin Scholars Program records, 2003-ongoing UA.01.08.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baldwin Scholars Program records
2003-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Baldwin Scholars Program
UA.01.08.0005
3.5 Linear Feet
The Baldwin Scholars Program at Duke University began during the 2004/2005 academic year. The Program aims to empower women to change Duke's campus culture and the world beyond. It is named for Alice M. Baldwin, the first dean of Duke University's Woman's College. Materials within the collection include program proposal, recruitment and publicity materials, newsletters, annual reports, group photographs of the Baldwin Scholars, and information about retreats, seminars, projects, and the scholars themselves. Material ranges in dates from 2003-ongoing.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Baldwin Scholars Program records were received by the University Archives as transfers between 2005-2017.
Biographical/Historical note
The Baldwin Scholars Program (BSP) at Duke University began during the 2004/2005 academic year. The Program aims to empower women to change Duke's campus culture and the world beyond. BSP is a four-year program for undergraduate women at Duke that gives students the opportunity to develop their critical thinking and problem solving skills, increase their personal awareness and growth, become connected to a strong and supportive network of peers and mentors, and work to realize their ambitions and dreams.
As Baldwin Scholars the students collectively take a first-year seminar and a senior capstone course, they live together on West Campus as sophomores, complete a career internship with a Duke alumna, and participate in numerous other activities and projects throughout the four years designed to enhance their leadership, critical thinking, and problem solving skills. The Program is named for Alice M. Baldwin, the first dean of Duke University's Woman's College.
Scope and Contents note
Collection contains materials pertaining to the formation and the operation of the Baldwin Scholars Program including the program proposal, recruitment and publicity materials, newsletter, annual reports, group photographs of the Baldwin Scholars, and information about retreats, seminars, and projects. Also included are the "Duke Inquiries in Gender: Report and Recommendation," and brief sketches of the Baldwin Scholars. Material ranges in dates from 2003-ongoing.
Related Material
Alice M. Baldwin papers, 1863-1961.
University Archives, Duke University.
Women -- Education (Higher) -- North Carolina -- Durham; Baldwin, Alice M. (Alice Mary), 1879-1960; Duke University. Baldwin Scholars Program
- 2004 news release (Box 1)
- 2003 Duke Inquiries in Gender (DIG) report (Box 1)
- 2003 Baldwin Scholars Program Proposal (Box 1)
- 2004 Fall poster campaign (Box 1)
- 2004 recruitment pieces (Box 1)
- 2004 recruitment and selection statistics (Box 1)
- 2004 Baldwin Scholars and photo (Box 1)
- 2004-2005 BSP e-newsletters (Box 1)
- 2004-2005 publicity (Box 1)
- 2005 Baldwin Scholars retreat (Box 1)
- 2005 first-year seminar (Box 1)
- 2004-2005 BSP programs (Box 1)
- 2004-2005 annual report (Box 2)
- 2004-2005 Giles Mentors (Box 2)
- 2005 recruitment pieces (Box 2)
- 2005 poster campaign (Box 2)
- 2005 recruitment and selection statistics (Box 2)
- 2005 Baldwin Scholars (Box 2)
- 2005-2006 BSP e-newsletters (Box 2)
- 2005-2006 publicity (Box 2)
- 2005-2006 BSP programs (Box 2)
- 2005-2006 leadership awards (Box 2)
- 2005-2006 Giles Mentors (Box 2)
- 2006 Baldwin Scholars retreat (Box 2)
- 2006 first-year seminar (Box 2)
- 2006 Images project (Box 2)
- 2007 Annual Report (Box 3)
- 2006 Fall poster campaign (Box 3)
- 2006 Recruitment (Box 3)
- 2006 Recruitment and selection ststistics (Box 3)
- 2006 Baldwin Scholars (Box 3)
- 2006-2007 e-newsletters (Box 3)
- 2006-2007 Publicity (Box 3)
- 2007 Baldwin Scholars retreat (Box 3)
- 2007 First year seminar, syllabi (Box 3)
- 2006-2007 Meeting minutes (Box 3)
- 2006-2007 BSP programs (Box 3)
- 2006-2007 Giles Mentors (Box 3)
- 2006-2007 Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- 2008 Annual report (Box 3)
- 2007 Fall poster campaign (Box 3)
- 2007 recruitment (Box 3)
- 2007 recruitment and selection statistics (Box 3)
- 2007 Baldwin scholars (Box 3)
- 2007-2008 e-newsletters (Box 3)
- 2007-2008 Publicity (Box 3)
- 2008 Baldwin Scholars retreat (Box 3)
- 2008 First-year seminar (Box 3)
- 2007 Senior Seminar (Box 3)
- 2007-2008 BSP events (Box 3)
- 2008 Unsung Heroine Award (Box 3)
- 2008 Commencement (Box 3)
- 2007-2008 miscellaneous (Box 3)
- 2008 Program Review (Box 4)
- 2008-2009 BSP Meetings (Box 4)
- 2008 Fall Poster Campaign (Box 4)
- 2008 Recruitment (Box 4)
- 2008 Recruitment and Selection Statistics (Box 4)
- Class of 2009 Baldwin Scholars (Box 4)
- Class of 2011 Baldwin Scholars (Box 4)
- Class of 2012 Baldwin Scholars (Box 4)
- 2008-2009 BSP e-newsletters (Box 4)
- 2008-2009 Publicity (Box 4)
- 2008 Senior Seminar (Box 4)
- 2008-2009 BSP Events (Box 4)
- 2008-2009 Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- 2009 Baldwin Scholars Retreat (Box 4)
- 2009 First Year Seminar (Box 4)
- 2009 Unsung Heroine Award (Box 4)
- 2009 Commencement (Box 4)
- 2009 Annual Report (Box 4)
- 2010 Annual Report (Box 4)
- 2009-2010 BSP Meeting Agendas (Box 4)
- 2009 Fall Poster Campaign (Box 4)
- 2009 Recruitment (Box 4)
- 2009 Recruitment and Selection Statistics (Box 4)
- Class of 2012 Baldwin Scholars (Box 4)
- 2009-2010 BSP E-Newsletters (Box 4)
- 2009-2010 Publicity (Box 4)
- 2010 Baldwin Scholars Retreat (Box 4)
- 2010 First Year Seminar (Box 4)
- 2009 senior seminar (Box 4)
- 2009-2010 BSP Events (Box 4)
- 2010 Unsung Heroine Award (Box 4)
- Class of 2010 Baldwin Scholars (Box 4)
- 2010 Commencement (Box 4)
- 2009-2010 Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- 2011 Annual Report (Box 5)
- 2010-11 BSP Meeting Minutes (Box 5)
- 2010 Fall Poster Campaign (Box 5)
- 2010 Recruitment (Box 5)
- 2010 Recruitment and Selection Statistics (Box 5)
- Class of 2014 Baldwin Scholars (Box 5)
- 2010-11 BSP E-Newsletters (Box 5)
- 2010-11 Publicity (Box 5)
- 2011 Baldwin Scholars Retreat (Box 5)
- 2011 First-Year Seminar (Box 5)
- 2010 Senior Seminar (Box 5)
- 2010-11 BSP Events (Box 5)
- 2011 Unsung Heroine Award (Box 5)
- Class of 2011 Baldwin Scholars (Box 5)
- 2011 Commencement (Box 5)
- 2011 Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- 2012 Annual Report (Box 6)
- 2011-2012 BSP Meeting Minutes (Box 6)
- 2011 Fall Poster Campaign (Box 6)
- 2011 Recruitment (Box 6)
- 2011 Recruitment and Selection Statistics (Box 6)
- Class of 2015 Baldwin Scholars (Box 6)
- 2011-2012 BSP E-Newsletters (Box 6)
- 2011-2012 Publicity (Box 6)
- 2012 Baldwin Scholars Retreat (Box 6)
- 2012 First Year Seminar (Box 6)
- 2011 Senior Seminar (Box 6)
- 2011-2012 BSP Events (Box 6)
- 2011-2012 BSP Projects (Box 6)
- 2012 Unsung Heroine Award (Box 6)
- Class of 2012 Baldwin Scholars (Box 6)
- 2012 Commencement (Box 6)
- 2011-2012 Miscellaneous (Box 6)
- 2013 Annual Report (Box 7)
- 2012-2013 BSP Meeting Minutes (Box 7)
- 2012 Fall Poster Campaign (Box 7)
- 2012 Recruitment (Box 7)
- 2012 Recruitment and Selection Statistics (Box 7)
- Class of 2016 Baldwin Scholars (Box 7)
- 2012-2013 E-Newsletters (Box 7)
- 2012-2013 Publicity (Box 7)
- 2013 Baldwin Scholars Retreat (Box 7)
- 2013 First Year Seminar (Box 7)
- 2012 Senior Seminar (Box 7)
- 2012-2013 BSP Events (Box 7)
- 2012-2013 BSP Projects (Box 7)
- 2013 Unsung Heroine Award (Box 7)
- Class of 2013 Baldwin Scholars (Box 7)
- 2013 Commencement (Box 7)
- 2012-2013 Miscellaneous (Box 7)
- 2014 Annual Report (Box 7)
- 2013-14 BSP Meeting Minutes (Box 7)
- 2013 Fall Poster Campaign (Box 7)
- 2013 Recruitment (Box 7)
- 2013 Recruitment and Selection Statistics (Box 7)
- Class of 2017 Baldwin Scholars (Box 7)
- 2013-14 BSP E-newsletters (Box 7)
- 2013-14 Publicity (Box 7)
- 2014 First-Year Seminar (Box 7)
- 2013 Senior Seminar (Box 7)
- 2013-14 BSP Events (Box 7)
- 2013-14 BSP Projects (Box 7)
- 2014 Unsung Heroine Award (Box 7)
- Class of 2014 Baldwin Scholars (Box 7)
- 2014 Commencement (Box 7)
- 2013-14 Miscellaneous (Box 7)
- The XY Campaign (2 folders) (Oversize-folder 1-2)
- 2015 Annual Report (Box 7)
- 2014-15 BSP Meeting Minutes (Box 7)
- 2014 Fall Poster Campaign (Box 7)
- 2014 Recruitment (Box 7)
- 2014 Recruitment and Selection Statistics (Box 7)
- Class of 2018 Baldwin Scholars (Box 7)
- 2014-15 BSP e-newsletters (Box 7)
- 2014-15 Publicity (Box 8)
- 2015 First-Year Seminar (Box 8)
- 2014 Senior Seminar (Box 8)
- 2014-15 BSP Events (Box 8)
- 2014-15 BSP Projects (Box 8)
- 2015 Unsung Heroine Award (Box 8)
- Class of 2015 Baldwin Scholars (Box 8)
- 2015 Commencement (Box 8)
- 2014-15 Miscellaneous (Box 8)
- #noapologies Posters, 2014-2015 (Oversize-folder 3)
- Fall2015 Poster Campaign (Oversize-folder 4)
- Event posters, 2015-2016 (Oversize-folder 4)
- SOC 180S Baldwin Scholars Seminar: Perceptions of the Self, Society, and the Natural World: Posters (Oversize-folder 4)
- Annual Report, 2015-2016 (Box 8)
- Fall poster campaign, 2015 (Box 8)
- Recruitment, 2015 (Box 8)
- Recruitment and Selection Statistics, 2015 (Box 8)
- Class of 2019 Baldwin Scholars, 2015 (Box 8)
- E-newsletters, 2015-2016 (Box 8)
- Publicity, 2015-2016 (Box 8)
- First-Year Seminar, 2016 (Box 8)
- Senior Seminar, 2015 (Box 8)
- Events, 2015-2016 (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous, 2015-2016 (Box 8)
- Unsung Heroine Award, 2016 (Box 8)
- 2016 Baldwin Scholars (Box 8)
- Commencement, 2016 (Box 8)
- Annual Report, 2017 (Box 8)
- Fall Poster Campaign, 2016 (Box 8)
- Recruitment, 2016 (Box 8)
- Recruitment and Selection Statistics, 2016 (Box 8)
- Class of 2020 Baldwin Scholars, 2016 (Box 8)
- BSP Newsletters, 2016-2017 (Box 8)
- Publicity, 2016-2017 (Box 8)
- First-Yeaar Seminar, 2017 (Box 8)
- Senior Seminar, 2016 (Box 8)
- BSP Events, 2016-2017 (Box 8)
- Unsung Heroine Award, 2017 (Box 8)
- Class of 2017 Baldwin Scholars (Box 8)
- Commencement, 2017 (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous, 2016-2017 (Box 8)
- Recruitment and Speaker Posters, 2016-2017 (Box 9)
- Annual Report, 2018 (Box 8)
- Fall poster campaign, 2017 (Box 8)
- Recruitment, 2017 (Box 8)
- Recruitment and selection statistics, 2017 (Box 8)
- Class of 2021 Baldwin Scholars, 2017 (Box 8)
- Baldwin Scholars Program e-newsletters, 2017-2018 (Box 8)
- Publicity, 2017 (Box 8)
- First-year seminar, 2018 (Box 8)
- Senior seminar, 2017 (Box 8)
- Baldwin Scholars Program events, 2017-2018 (Box 8)
- Unsung Heroine award, 2018 (Box 8)
- Class of 2018 Baldwin Scholars (Box 8)
- Commencement, 2018 (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous, 2017-2018 (Box 8)
- Recruitment and event posters, 2017-2018 (Box 9)
- Annual Report, 2019 (Box 10)
- Fall Poster Campaign, 2018 (Box 10)
- Recruitment, 2018 (Box 10)
- Recruitment and Selection Statistics, 2018 (Box 10)
- Class of 2022 Baldwin Scholars (Box 10)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Photograph
- Publicity, 2018-2019 (Box 10)
- First Year Seminar, 2019 (Box 10)
- Senior Seminar, 2018 (Box 10)
- BSP Events, 2018-2019 (Box 10)
- Class of 2019 Baldwin Scholars (Box 10)
- Commencement, 2019 (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous, 2018-2019 (Box 10)
- Recruitment and event posters, 2018-2019 (Box 9)